<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>MarcoPolo – Partially Functional - Books</title>
	<author><name>Marco</name></author>
	<link href="https://marcopolo.io/books/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://marcopolo.io/books/"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2019-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://marcopolo.io/books/atom.xml</id>
	
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A review of _No One At The Wheel_ by Samuel Schwartz</title>
		<published>2019-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://marcopolo.io/books/no-one-at-the-wheel/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://marcopolo.io/books/no-one-at-the-wheel/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;no-one-at-the-wheel-driverless-cars-and-the-road-of-the-future&quot;&gt;No One At The Wheel: Driverless Cars and the road of the Future&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked this book up after listening to Schwartz talk on &lt;em&gt;Fresh Air&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Schwartz
is a traffic engineer, who worked at the chief traffic engineer for NYC. I was
interested in this book because it adds a healthy dose of skepticism to all the
hype I&#x27;ve heard about self-driving cars. I expected him to say &amp;quot;The future will
be perfect, self driving cars will solve all our problems&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;The future is
terrible, self driving cars will run over all the babies&amp;quot;. Instead, he was in an
informed center. He acknowledges a lot of benefits AVs (autonomous vehicles) can
bring, refutes some hollow claims from advocates, and points out several
pitfalls to avoid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is an easy read and goes by quickly. I mostly listened to it,
amusingly enough, from a drive from Montana to California (where I
wished I had a self driving car to make the drive easier).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schwartz refutes some ideas about AVs that I thought were a given. First is
that AVs, and AVs alone, will reduce traffic fatalities to nil. It&#x27;s true that
AVs can introduce technology that will reduce traffic fatalities, but it is also
true that &lt;strong&gt;right now&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; we have that technology that we can incorporate in non
self driving vehicles. Technologies like front collision warning (reduces accidents
by 7%), automatic front collision braking (reduces accidents by 15%), and lane
detection are available today. These technologies are shown to make driving
safer, but they are only available on high end luxury vehicles. We have the
power today to make the roads vastly safer overnight by passing legislation to
make these safety features standard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book warns of a dystopia future where everyone ones their own AV. In this
world traffic is continually clogged and up to half of the cars in traffic are
empty. People drive much more because it is that much easier. They sacrifice the
exercise they would have gained in biking or walking by choosing the easier
option of watching a movie while waiting in deadlock traffic. In this future,
AVs are more like phones. A new model coming out every year or so, and people
upgrading just as often. All the new production would have an obvious adverse
effect on climate. Likewise the increase in traffic would be terrible for the
environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The happy future Schwartz talks about is a future where AVs work with traffic
engineers to complement existing transit infrastructure. There could be AV
buses that could run much more frequently on more routes 24&#x2F;7 that would extend
existing public transit routes. Autonomous mini buses can be used to create a
route on demand for the rush hour commuters to bring them to a bigger transit
hub (e.g. a subway). Smaller AVs can then be used in the off hours to get people
to their nearest transit hub, thus solving the last mile problem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schwartz sprinkles his book with parallels from the time cars where first
introduced. Roads where first made for cyclist. Cyclist were lobbying for more
roads around the time cars were being introduced. As cars became more ubiquitous
and faster, bicyclist and pedestrians were kicked off the roads and
criminalized. Roads took over and changed our cities into desolate avenues with
drivers careening through city centers at 40mph. Schwartz argues, and I&#x27;m
inclined to agree, we cannot let AVs push everyone else as second class
citizens. We are at an inflection point where we can define legislation to
prioritize pedestrians and city life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;smile.amazon.com&#x2F;dp&#x2F;B07B8JGG5M&#x2F;ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1&amp;amp;sa-no-redirect=1&quot;&gt;this book&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Thoughts on _The Craftsman_ by Richard Sennet</title>
		<published>2019-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://marcopolo.io/books/the-craftsman-sennet/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://marcopolo.io/books/the-craftsman-sennet/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve finished my second read through of &lt;em&gt;The Craftsman&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. It&#x27;s an argument that
craftsman are more capable than society gives than credit for. The notion of
&lt;em&gt;animal laborens&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, that man is simply a thoughtless animal, is wrong in Sennet&#x27;s
view. He argues that we think deeply when we work with our hands. The woodworker
isn&#x27;t just idly planing away at the wood she&#x27;s working on. She looks at the
grain, analyzes the constraints of the material, and is constantly problem
solving &lt;em&gt;and&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; problem finding. The same applies to programmers. Fixing bugs is
never a simple tasks. Often it challenges both our problem solving and problem
finding abilities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sennet decorates his book with interesting case studies. The skill involved in
using a Chinese cleaver or the expressive metaphorical recipe of how to cook a
specific chicken dish are a couple of memorable examples. Sennet analyzes the
history of the craftsman from ancient times to today, and how the industrial
revolution has changed the scene. He asks Voltaire, with his encyclopedia, for
his thoughts to accompany his own. Voltaire understood the superiority of machines
in certain craft tasks, but felt it wasn&#x27;t fair to the craftsman to focus only
on that superiority. The craftsman has the ability through problem solving and
problem finding to use these new machines as tools.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the story of &amp;quot;honest&amp;quot; bricks especially interesting. There was a time
when the only way to make bricks was the artisanal and very labor intensive way.
The bricks in these cases all came out slightly different and imbued with colors
that represented the geographic origin and creators. Then came a more industrial
form of creating bricks. This process created many bricks at uniform sizes and
colors very cheaply. At this point people started to personify the bricks. They
called bricks &amp;quot;honest&amp;quot; when they were hand made with blemishes that reflect
their creation. No one doubted that the industrial bricks where objectively
better, but there was still a considerable demand for these honest bricks. The
industrial process eventually came up with ways to emulate more characteristics
of the honest brick, such as modifying the colors of the bricks to mirror those
of bricks from smaller towns. Even though this happened several hundred years
ago and in another country, I think it&#x27;s very easy to relate to this story.
We are essentially reliving this, but with everything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The myth of Pandora and Hephaestus are brought again and again throughout the
book. The myths highlight the paradox in craft and society. Hephaestus was a
skilled craftsman but an ugly person (born with a club foot). Pandora, a
beautiful goddess with a box of ugly and evil things. The myths are the original
prototype of society&#x27;s fears and beliefs on crafts. Frankenstein is a more modern
version of Pandora&#x27;s box. Parts of the movie &lt;em&gt;Jiro Dreams of Sushi&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is our
modern &lt;em&gt;Hymn to Hephaestus&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the book is unbelievably fascinating in so many ways. It reminds me of
when I heard &lt;em&gt;Marian Hill&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; for the first time. I didn&#x27;t even realize music could
sound that way. I was so happy to have discovered a whole new facet of life that
I didn&#x27;t even know existed. The book is the same way. Every chapter introduces
some thought or history that I never knew existed. Each page was like Christmas.
A nice gift from Sennet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only have a few issues with the book. The biggest one is likely it&#x27;s weight
on the idea that a society of skilled craftsmen could result in a society closer
to self governance. An idea close to Jefferson. Perhaps it&#x27;s because I&#x27;ve been
reading Ron Chernow&#x27;s Hamilton biography, but I&#x27;m primed to be suspect of
Jefferson&#x27;s political theories. I&#x27;m surprised by Sennet&#x27;s belief here as he
classifies a lot of somewhat surprising things as crafts (parenting, experience,
etc.), but doesn&#x27;t seem to classify governance and politics as a craft.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s a great book, and I&#x27;d recommend it. I was introduced to it from Paul
Sellers. Here&#x27;s an excerpt of his thoughts on it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read an article about skilled artisans producing designs and selling their
wares to mainstream in a recent weekend issue of the Observer written by Emma
Love. In two minutes I thought to myself this surely has to be a joke. ... It
was filled with journalistic drivel where she used stock phrases of the day like
“Traditional skills”, “Tapping into the wider trend for natural materials,”.
What she didn’t see was that most of the goods were highly over priced and none
of them used traditional skills anywhere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish that this journalist read a little more. I wish she had read this book
beforehand, perhaps she might have at least understood she didn’t understand;
that she couldn’t understand. Richard Sennett’s book is a well researched
masterpiece, unpretentious in every sphere and should be mandatory reading for
any and all craft students and mentored apprentices true to their craft. Sennett
carefully crafts his sentences with depth and meaning of an artisan, and whereas
I might not agree with every single word, I do see that he worked extremely
diligently to open the world Pandora left to get a point of view in place first
and then blasted through the myths and mysteries of why we do what we do, why
penchants exist as yearnings beyond our understandings and why, when we are
young, we should indeed listen to our hearts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;paulsellers.com&#x2F;2018&#x2F;03&#x2F;theres-a-book-you-should-read&#x2F;&quot;&gt;There&#x27;s a book you should read&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
